Guide to the Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children, Allegheny County Chapter Records, 1952-1965 AIS.1966.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Scholarships and Awards, 1955-1956; XI.
  This series has information on scholarships and awards granted by PARC.
  - Scholarships (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Awards and Grants, 1955-1956 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Awards and Scholarships (Box 26, Folder 3-6)
  - Scholarships (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Articles, 1954-1964; XII.
  This series consists of articles pertaining to mentally retarded children. The files are arranged alphabetically. The miscellaneous folders contain reports, employment and volunteer information, convention notes, financial reports, membership lists, meeting minutes and correspondence.
  - Articles (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Behavioral Sciences Research on Mental Retardation: Development and Prospects, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Bibliography (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Brain-injured (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Cerebral Palsy (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Chlorpromayine Hydrochloride (Largactil) (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Clinics (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Community (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Condensation (books) (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Counseling (Parents and Children) (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Crippled Children (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Directory of Health, Education, Welfare and Allied Services (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Editorial, May, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Epilepsy (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Equipment - Catalogs (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Facts about Mental Retardation (Box 27, Folder 16-17)
  - Films for the Asking (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Film royalties - show business (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - From the state Capitals, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Government Aid (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Handicrafts (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Health (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Help (for the parents and retarded) (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Helping the Mentally Retarded: A Report for 1960-1961 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Historian (clippings) (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Homes (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Home School Reporters, January, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Home Training (Box 28, Folder 8-9)
  - Hospital (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Hydrocephalus (water on brain) (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Institutional Placement for Children, by Gale H. Walker, M.D. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Institutions (Box 28, Folder 13-14)
  - International Council for Exceptional Children (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Loose and Miscellaneous Material (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Mental Health Agency (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Mental Health (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Literature (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Mongolism (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Article on the Treatment of Mongolism with Dehydroepiandrosterone, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Muscular Dystrophy (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - National Recreation Association Certificate, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - New Equipment (Box 29, Folder 2-3)
  - New Medical Knowledge about Mental Retardation (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Ontario Association for Retarded Children (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
  - Prevention (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Procedures (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Publications by Retarded Groups (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Reading (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Recreation (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Red Cross (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Religion (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Scouting (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Services to the Mental Retarded and His Family, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Speech (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Speeches (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Toys (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - The Training School Bulletin, 1954-1958 (Box 30, Folder 6-8)
  - U.S. Government Publications, Supt of Documents, Government Printing Office (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Vineland Training School (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1963-1964 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 30, Folder 12-15)
- Miscellaneous Material, 1958-1960 and undated; XIII.
  This series contains miscellaneous information about the Chapter.
  - Mimeographing (Box 31, Folder 1-4)
  - Mimeograph Artwork (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous folders (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Job descriptions (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Office inventory (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Staff Chart, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Policies, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Advisory Board, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 11)
- PARC/NARC, 1952-1963; XIV.
  The data in this series deals with PARC and NARC.
  - Other PARC Chapters, 1952-1954 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - PARC - List of County Chapters, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - PARC, 1953-1955 (Box 31, Folder 14-16)
  - Office, 1956-1957 (Box 31, Folder 17-18)
  - PARC, 1958-1961 (Box 32, Folder 1-9)
  - Children Limited (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Meeting, May 1, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Meeting, September 8, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Thank-You Letters, 1956-1959 (Box 32, Folder 13-14)
  - PARC Allegheny County Chapter. Newsletter. (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Allegheny Story of Mental Retardation (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - National Association for Retarded Children (NARC)
    - Constitution and By-laws, 1950, 1958, and 1959 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Board of Directors, Minutes, 1958-1960 (Box 32, Folder 18-19)
    - Board of Directors, Minutes, 1961-1963 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - First Report of Executive Director, 5th Annual Convention, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1955-1960 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Proposed Budget, 1961 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Budget Committee (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Reports of Various Committees (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Annual Convention (Highlights), Houston, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Convention, Material on 7th Annual Convention, October 25-27, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - 8th Annual Convention - ST. Louis - October 8-13, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - 9th Annual Convention - Philadelphia, October 8-11, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Convention in Cincinnati, 1959 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Annual Convention, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - PARC (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Northeast Regional Conference. Wilmington, Delaware, June 5-7, 1959 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Draft. Suggestions for Present and Future Programming of the ACC-PARC, June 22, 1959 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - The Record Newsletter (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - National Association for Retarded Children (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Trends and Issues in Mental Retardation. White House Conference on Children and Youth, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - National Association for Retarded Children, 1953-1955 (Box 34, Folder 6-7)
    - Correspondence, Memoranda, 1958-1963 (Box 34, Folder 8-19)
    - Publications and Pamphlets (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Research Fund (Box 34, Folder 21-22)
    - PARC (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - PARC membership (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - NARC, 1959-1962 (Box 34, Folder 25)